＜５年以下の懲役 または➡
50万円以下の
罰金に処せられます＞
＜後悔しても 元には戻せない＞
不正視聴!?
(サクモ)しかし お前も俺も➡
Who would have thought that
both you and I would die so early?
こうも早死にするとはな。
Although not as early as your mother.
母さんほどじゃなかったが…。
(カカシ)父さん 俺ずっと
言いたいことがあったんだ。
Father, I've always wanted
to ask you something.
なんで 木ノ葉の白い牙と呼ばれた
英雄の父さんが➡
Why did someone like you, who was
known as the White Fang of the Leaf
choose to ignore the village code
大切な里の掟を破って
仲間の命を助けるために➡
and abandon a crucial mission
in order to save his comrades?
任務を中断することを
選んだのか…。
If you had not done so,
そんなことしなければ➡
父さんは 誰にも
責められることもなく➡
no one would have condemned you and
you wouldn't have become so miserable.
自分で自分を追い込むことも
なかったのにって…。
悔しかった…。
I felt so bitter.
そうか お前も それなりに
大変だったようだな。
I see...
You took it pretty hard, didn't you?
あぁ…。
Yeah.
でもね 父さん…。
But you know, Father...
Whatever the outcome,
I know you did your best.
結果はどうあれ
父さんは精一杯やったよ。
今なら 父さんを理解できる。
I can see that now
and I understand you.
みんなのために
掟を破った父さんを➡
You broke the code to save everyone.
And I'm proud of you for it.
今は 誇りに思う。
(サクモ)ありがとう。
Thank you.
なんだ!?
What is that?!
(リー)なんです!? あの光は！
What is that light?!
(フカサク)母ちゃん
ここは どこじゃ？
Ma? Where am I?
(シマ)ギャ～ッ！
- Whoa!
- What's going on, Guy Sensei?
(ガイ)うおっ！
(リー)これは いったい!?
ガイ先生！
I see!
《サクラ : フカサク様は
確実に死んでいた。
Lord Fukasaku was definitely dead!
And yet...
What just happened?!
何なの？ これ。
いったい 何が起こったの？》
バ バカな…。 こんなことが…。
I-Impossible!
How can such a thing occur?!
(シカマル)どういうことだ？
What's going on?
(木ノ葉丸)イルカ先生！
Iruka Sensei!
(イルカ)無事だったのか！
先生もだ コレ！
- You're alive!
- You too, Sensei!
エビス先生 お怪我を？
(エビス)かすり傷ですよ。
Ebisu Sensei, are you hurt?
This is nothing.
木ノ葉丸君に助けられました。
エヘヘヘ…。
Konohamaru saved me.
今は 私の傷のことより
この現象です。
But never mind my injury.
What is this phenomenon?
えぇ…。
Yes...
(いのいち)これは…。
What in the world?!
(シカク)どうやら
ナルトの決着は ついたようだな。
It seems Naruto has settled things.
Hero of the Hidden Leaf
What? What just happened?!
(ナルト)何だ…？
何が起こったんだってばよ!?
The villagers are coming back to life,
one after another.
(カツユ)里の人たちが
どんどん生き返っています。
What?! You mean...
えっ!? それって…。
I'll stay here and
look after them for a while.
((自来也 : わしは しばらく
こいつらの面倒をみる。
Just until they can take
better care of themselves.
多少 自立ができるように
なるまでだがな。
It's the least I can do.
(これが せめてもの償いだ))
I'm still in time to revive those I've killed
since arriving in the Leaf Village.
(長門)木ノ葉に来て
俺が殺めた者たちなら➡
まだ間に合う。
これが せめてもの償いだ。
It's the least
I can do for them.
これは…。
What's this?
Seems it was too soon for you
to come here.
どうやら お前は
ここに来るには早すぎたようだ。
There must be something
you're still meant to do.
お前には まだ
やるべきことがあるはずだ。
父さん…。
Father...
お前と話せてよかった。
I'm glad we got to talk.
俺を許してくれて ありがとう。
Thank you for forgiving me.
Now I can move on in peace.
これで 安心していける…。
(サクモ)母さんに
やっと会えるよ…。
I'll finally be able to see your mother.
- Pa!
- Yes.
(チョウジ)あっ！ 父ちゃん！
(チョウザ)ん？
やはり カカシもか。
Kakashi too, eh?
What's going on?
これは…。
よかった… よかったよ カカシ先生！
Thank goodness!
I'm so glad, Kakashi Sensei!
I will explain everything.
私が すべて説明します。
ハァ… ハァ…。
お前…。
You...
War inflicts death, injury,
and pain to both sides.
戦いとは 双方に 死と傷と痛みを
伴わせるものだ。
大切な人の死ほど
受け入れられず➡
The death of someone dear
is hard to accept.
We convince ourselves
there's no way they could die.
死ぬはずがないと
都合よく思い込む。
特に 戦争を知らない
お前たちの世代は しかたがない。
It especially can't be helped
with your generation.
You don't know war.
You may try to find meaning in death,
but there is only pain.
死に 意味を見出そうとするが➡
あるのは 痛みと➡
An unbearable hatred...
どこにぶつけていいかわからない
憎しみだけ。
Senseless deaths...
ゴミのような死と➡
Eternal hatred...
And pain that does not heal.
永久に続く憎しみと
癒えない痛み…。
That's what war is.
それが戦争だ。
Naruto... This is what you
will be facing in time.
ナルト… お前が これから➡
立ち向かうことに
なってくるものだ。
フッ… 本といい お前といい➡
Regarding that book, and you...
It feels like someone set it up.
誰かが すべて仕組んだ
ことのように思える。
Or... Perhaps this is the real work of a god.
いや… これこそが
本当の神の仕業なのか…。
It seems my work ends here, Naruto.
俺の役目は ここまでのようだ…。
ナルト お前だったら 本当に…。
I believe you can bring true peace.
そいつも 連れて帰んのか？
You're taking this one with you too?
(小南)ええ このペイン天道こそ
弥彦の亡骸で作ったもの。
Yes... Tendo Pain was created
from Yahiko's body.
私たちにとっては 大切な人。
弥彦って そいつだったのか。
He is very precious to us.
So he was...Yahiko.
お前は どうするんだ？
So what are you going to do?
I hate to think that
you're returning to the Akatsuki.
もう暁に戻るとは
思いたくねえけど。
暁は抜ける。 私にとっては
弥彦と長門が すべてだった。
I'm leaving the Akatsuki.
Yahiko and Nagato meant
everything to me.
弥彦の夢 そして 長門の夢。
Yahiko's dream...
And Nagato's dream...
２人の夢が お前に託されたなら
これからは お前が２人の夢だ。
If both of their dreams have been
passed on to you,
then you now embody their dreams.
長門がお前を信じたなら
私は お前を信じる。
Nagato put his faith in you.
So will I.
私たち雨隠れは お前とともに➡
We, the Hidden Rain,
will pursue their dreams with you.
２人の夢を
追いかけることにしよう。
((答えが
見つからんかったときは➡
If I can't find the answer,
perhaps I'll entrust you to find it!
その答えを
お前に託すとしようかのぉ。
(お前を信じてみよう。
うずまきナルト))
I think I shall believe in you...
Naruto Uzumaki.
ナルトって名前と
あきらめないド根性。
The name Naruto,
the guts to never give up,
and pain.
それから痛み。
それが 師匠と
兄弟子から譲り受けたもんだ。
That's what I inherited from my teacher
and sibling disciple!
This time...
今度こそ お前は散ることのない
希望の花であってくれ。
I pray that you will be the blossom of hope
that never wilts.
見ててくれ 師匠。
Just you watch, Master!
MASTER
TALES OF A GUTSY NINJA
よくやったな。
カカシ先生。
Good job.
Kakashi Sensei...
Just lean on me.
そのまま背にいろ。
《重くなったな》
He's gotten heavy.
Hmm?
よく帰ってきた。
信じてたぞ。
Welcome back!
We knew you could do it!
They've all been awaiting your return.
みんな
お前が帰るのを待ってたんだ。
((将来の夢は 火影を超す！
My dream is to surpass the Hokage!
And make everyone in
the village acknowledge me!
(んでもって 里のやつら全員に
俺の存在を認めさせてやるんだ))
《ナルト よく頑張ったな》
Naruto... You did well.
おかえり！
ナルト！
Welcome back!
Naruto!
な… なんで？
Wh-What's going on?
事の顛末は すべて
私を通して伝えておきました。
I relayed every detail of
the events that occurred.
Hey! What was the enemy like?
ねぇねぇ 敵はどんなだった？
Are you hurt?
怪我してない？
いてっ！ 押すなってばよ。
Oww! Don't push!
《ヒナタ : よかった ナルト君》
I'm so glad, Naruto.
Hey! Cut it out!
こら！ いいかげんに やめ…。
あ… サクラちゃん。
Sakura...
You're so reckless, you idiot!
無茶ばっかりして このバカ！
ありがとう。
Thank you.
Way to go, Naruto.
やりましたね ナルト君。
おぉ！ あれこそ まさに青春だ。
Yes! That's what youth is!
ほんとに１人で
やりやがるとはな。
I can't believe
he pulled it off all by himself.
うん うん。
Uh-huh...
I could almost fall for him.
(いの)ちょっと惚れちゃうかも。
えっ!?
- Huh?!
(キバ)ナルトのやつ やるじゃねえか。
さっすが俺の同期。
Ain't he something, that Naruto.
That's my classmate!
He really outclassed us.
(シノ)ずいぶん
差をつけられたものだな。
Shut up.
We'll make it up starting now!
うるせえ。
巻き返しは こっからだ。
イルカ先生 俺らも行くぞ。
Let's join them, Iruka Sensei!
いいんだ… ここで。
No, I'm fine right here.
でも！
まあまあ。
- But...
- Now, now...
すごいですね ナルト君は…。
Naruto is amazing, isn't he?
はじめは この私を含め➡
At first, everyone thought he was
such a nuisance, including myself.
皆が彼のことを
厄介者だと思っていました。
その宿命を恐れるあまり
遠巻きにして➡
We feared his destiny,
so we kept him at arm's length
関わろうとはしなかった。
and didn't bother with him.
((狐のガキは
忍者にするべきではない！
That fox kid shouldn't
become a ninja!
三代目は何を考えておられる!?
What is the Third Hokage thinking?!
あのカカシ班 テロリストの再不斬を
倒したんだってよ。
That Team Kakashi...
I heard they defeated
the terrorist Zabuza!
どうやら
九尾の子が活躍したらしい。
Sounds like the Nine-Tails kid
had a part in it...
No way...
I heard he was a loser.
ウソ？ あれは落ちこぼれって
聞いてたけど。
どうせ カカシさんの力でしょ。
I bet it was Kakashi's doing.
あの九尾の子が
中忍試験で本戦に出るみたいだな。
I hear that Nine-Tails kid made it
to the Finals of the Chunin Exam.
ウソだろ!?
あいつ意外とやるもんだな。
Are you serious?!
He's more skilled than I thought.
フン… 化け狐が
暴走しなけりゃいいけどね。
Humph! I just hope the fox demon
doesn't go on a rampage.
おぉ！
Oh!
あれが例の子か？
That's that fox kid?
日向に勝つなんて…。
I can't believe he won against a Hyuga.
それも すばらしい
試合だったじゃないか！
That was an awesome match!
(コテツ)あの狐のガキが
こんな戦いをするとはな。
I never expected such
a battle from the fox kid.
(イズモ)たいしたガキだ))
He's quite a boy.
しかし どんなときも
決してあきらめない彼の姿勢と➡
However, he never ever gave up.
まっすぐな忍道を
見せつけられて➡
And he stayed true to his Ninja Way.
少しずつ 彼を
認めざるを得なくなっていました。
And slowly, but surely
we couldn't help but acknowledge him.
((こん… ちくしょう！
D-Da...
Damn it!
砂の人柱力から
里を守ったらしいわよ。
I heard he protected the village from
the Sand Jinchuruki!
誰が？
うずまきナルトよ ほら あの例の。
Who did?
Naruto Uzumaki.
You know, the one...
五代目火影様が決まってよかった。
これで里も ひと安心だ。
I'm so glad the Fifth Hokage
has been decided!
We can breathe a little easier now.
自来也様とナルトのおかげだな。
Thanks to Lord Jiraiya and Naruto!
大蛇丸とも
やり合ったってほんと？
Is it true they fought Orochimaru?
(サスケ)ぐっ！
うちはのサスケは
連れ返せなかったらしいよ。
I heard they couldn't bring
Sasuke Uchiha back.
ナルトのやつ
落ち込んでなきゃいいが…。
I hope Naruto isn't too depressed.
どうやら 暁ってやつらが
人柱力を狙ってるみたいだ。
A group named the Akatsuki
is after the Jinchuriki.
となると
ナルトも狙われちまうってことか？
Which means Naruto will
also be targeted.
大丈夫なのか？
Will he be okay?
Lord Jiraiya will look out
for Naruto.
ナルトは自来也様が見てくれる。
なんでも 暁から
砂の風影をナルトが助けたそうだ。
I heard that Naruto rescued
the Sand's Kagekaze from the Akatsuki!
これで砂隠れと木ノ葉
仲よくできるといいな。
Wouldn
自来也様が 暁にやられた！
ナルトは大丈夫か!?
ナルトは
自来也様の意志を受け継いでる。
へこたれちゃいないよ。
(あいつは
いつものように進むだけさ))
今では皆
心からナルト君のことを信じ➡
案じ 期待し 願っている。
彼は 本当に多くの人々の心を
変えてしまった。
あいつは… 頑張りましたから。
((イルカよ。
何です？ 火影様。
お前の気持 わからんでもないが
あやつも お前と同じだ。
親の愛情を知らず 里の者には
あの事件のことで煙たがられる。
だから 人の気を引くために…
イタズラをするしかなかったのじゃ。
どんなかたちであれ➡
自分の存在価値を
認めてほしかったのじゃよ。
四代目は 里の者たちに
ナルトを英雄として見てほしかった。
(そう願って封印し 死んだ))
《三代目… 四代目…》
《今 目の前に英雄がいます》
(ウルティア)大魔闘演武
いよいよ始まるわね。
(メルディ)ジェラールってば
結局 参加しちゃうんだもんな。
これなら危険をおかして→
フェアリーテイルに会いに行った意味
ないんじゃない？
意味はあったんじゃない？
少なくともジェラールと エルザには。